Kenzi Connor

Staff Software Engineer - VP Engineering - Director of Engineering - CEO & CTO

CLIENTS

American Cancer Society · One Medical / Amazon · Bank of New York Mellon · Commvault · Fastly · Gusto · Public Library of Science · World Health Organization · Vital Strategies · Key Fortune 50s

SUMMARY

20+ years of engineering, engineering management, and executive leadership High-compliance spaces: fin/edu/health/gov tech High-throughput, low-latency, low-downtime systems Management of cross-functional teams and cross-team collabs Resilience in high-pressure situations: rush jobs & very high-profile clients Management of client relationships and all aspects of businesses

EXPERIENCE

CEO & CTO - Cloud City Development

2011 - PRESENT

Founded and grew to 35 person software design + development firm Principal Engineer and CTO consultant for clients Built teams that IPO'ed, got acquired, and secured \$100s of millions in funding

CTO & Advisor - OKCupid Labs for Match.com

2011 - 2013

Built eng. team from 0 to mid 30 headcount within 7 months
Weekly strategy sessions for dozens of properties, with tens of millions of users
Managed full redesign and re-architecture of the largest of these properties.
Established effective engineering team that could continue to deliver after I left

Senior Software Engineer - Pivotal Labs

2010 - 2011

Emergency jill-of-all-trades across both complex frontend and high-scale backend Ramped up quickly on 4 projects in 7 months, contributing effectively immediately Built developer infrastructure for high-scale, no-downtime migration from VPS to AWS Debugged mass-scale throughput/IO concurrency limitations

Senior Software Engineer - Yieldbuild

2007 - 2010

Co-authored nginx & Rack handlers w/ billions of monthly uniques Built primary reporting/data site with dynamic data-viz in Flex Framework and infrastructure updates with a zero-downtime requirement. Optimized payloads of .js to within individual IP packet size constraints.

CEO & CTO - InfoSauce

2003 - 2011

Co-founded and grew 10 person software design + development firm Principal Engineer and CTO consultant for clients Continued to develop high-profile (NDA'd) banking clients

Lead Developer - BridgeLine Software

2002 - 2003

Technical contact and head dev for Wall Street/financial work with global roll-outs.

Developer - Hall Kinion

2001 - 2002

Rebuilt mortgage services app from Access DB to current web frameworks

EDUCATION

<u>Presidential Scholar full-ride - University of Utah</u>

Honors major in CS; minors in math, physics, chemistry (one class left). Could have attended anywhere, but trying for World Cup in Freestyle Skiing Dropped out to found a tech company

TECHNICAL

Rust, Ruby, Javascript

- Technical Architecture
- Infra/CI+CD/DevOps
- · Git, Bash/zsh, CLI, Posix
- · GitHub Actions, chef
- Agile / XP / TDD
- A/B Testing
- PostareSOL, MvSOL, etc
- HBase/HDFS, MongoDB, Redis, Memcache, CouchDB
- Ruby on Rails, Node.is
- HTML, CSS, XML, SCSS

Previously:

C, C++, Lisp, C#, Java, Python, Flash, Flex, ActionScript, ASP, VBScript, VB COM, MSSQL

OTHER SKILLS

Executive Leadership Engineering Management Hiring / Retention Consultative Sales

CURRENT FOSS

knz.ai/cega

Rust library for parsing CGA/EGA graphics binaries knz.ai/zola-build Github Action to deploy Rust static site gen to GH Pages

MENTORSHIP

Dev Bootcamp Mills College MIT MakerHealth ProInspire Rails Bridge Rails Girls

SPEAKING

RubyConf Madison Ruby

LINKS & CONTACT

linkedin.com/in/knzai twitter.com/knzconnor github.com/knzai knz.ai/resume/ resume@knz.ai Oakland, CA, 94602

PURSUITS inc. FORMER

- #36 US Dual Mogul Skiing
- Wing Chun (Kung Fu)
- Circus Arts (straps and acro)
- #1-2 weekly SHL2 Oz DM